- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
Kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
Kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
kids: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
孩子们：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
All:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
[flute plays]
[长笛演奏]
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[bright music]
[明亮的音乐]
♪ ♪
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
- [grunts] Yes!
- [咕哝]是的！
My new Tootsie Trampler
is finally complete!
我的新 Tootsie Trampler
终于完成了！
At last, I will be the stomper,
not the stompee.
最后，我将成为践踏者，
不是踩踏者。
[laughs maniacally]
[疯狂地笑]
[stomping]
[跺脚]
Ouch, Karen!
Help!
哎哟，凯伦！
帮助！
- I think we have company.
- 我想我们有同伴。
Oh, here.
Let's exfoliate you.
哦，在这里。
让我们给你去角质吧。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[melodic horn honks]
[旋律号角鸣响]
- Who is that?
- 那是谁？
[bright music]
[明亮的音乐]
Holy moly macarooney.
圣莫里通心粉。
Huh?
[grunts]
啊？
[咕哝]
- Howdy, son!
- 你好，儿子！
- Ma? Pa?
- 妈？爸？
- Karen, is that a new monitor?
- 凯伦，那是新显示器吗？
- Oh, you charmer.
[giggles]
-哦，你这个迷人的人。
[咯咯笑]
- Knock it off, Romeo.
- 别闹了，罗密欧。
- Huh?
- 啊？
How could you afford
this ridiculous monstrosity?
你怎么能负担得起
这个可笑的怪物？
- Your ma and me
won the lottery...
- 你妈妈和我
中了彩票...
- [laughs]
- So we moved to the big city.
- [笑]
- 所以我们搬到了大城市。
Just like our
too-fancy-for-pants son.
就像我们的
太花哨的儿子。
- We got ourselves a butler.
- 我们给自己找了个管家。
- Your spittoon, madam?
- 你的痰盂吗，女士？
Very good.
非常好。
- Want a tour of the vehicle?
- 想要参观车辆吗？
- Not really.
- Come on in!
- 并不真地。
- 进来吧！
- Oh, real classy.
- 哦，真优雅。
- Purty fancy, ain't it?
- 很花哨，不是吗？
- That depends
on your definition
- 这取决于
根据你的定义
of pretty and fancy.
[screams]
漂亮又花哨。
[尖叫声]
- Our new homestead on wheels
has all the creature comforts.
- 我们带轮子的新家园
拥有一切物质享受。
- Like this velvet
feeding trough for Elmer.
- 就像这个天鹅绒
埃尔默的喂食槽。
Now, he can wallow
in luxury instead of filth.
现在，他可以沉溺其中
奢华而不是肮脏。
- No, Elmer!
Put me down! Ow!
- 不，埃尔默！
放我下来！噢！
- And a side-by-side outhouse
for them romantical evenings.
- 并排的户外厕所
为他们打造浪漫的夜晚。
Mwah!
[flushes]
哇！
[脸红]
- Plus, there's room
for the whole Plankton clan.
- 另外，还有空间
对于整个浮游生物家族。
ALL: Howdy!
全体：你好！
[friendly chatter]
[友好的闲聊]
- Ugh, hello.
- 呃，你好。
So how long
are you visiting for?
那么多久
你来访是为了？
Seven, five,
maybe three minutes?
七、五、
也许三分钟？
- We're here to stay, son.
- 我们会留下来，儿子。
We're following
your lead and starting up
我们正在关注
你的领导和启动
our own restaurant.
我们自己的餐厅。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
♪ ♪
- The Spud Bucket!
- 马铃薯桶！
[upbeat bluegrass music]
[欢快的蓝草音乐]
- What in the wha?
- 哇什么？
♪ ♪
- Guess what's on the menu.
- 猜猜菜单上有什么。
- Let me guess, potatoes?
- 让我猜猜，土豆？
- Oh, you done peeked.
We got tater sandwiches.
- 哦，你偷看了。
我们得到了土豆泥三明治。
- Spud cakes.
- 马铃薯蛋糕。
- Our fresh squeezed
tater juice.
- 我们的鲜榨
马铃薯汁。
[cow moos]
[牛哞哞]
- Ugh.
Ah!
- 呃。
啊!
- Just for the kids,
tater balloons.
- 只为了孩子们，
塔特气球。
[together]
Ow!
[一起]
噢！
And the coup de grace,
Spud Surprise.
还有致命一击，
马铃薯惊喜。
Oh, Cousin Cletus!
- Yep!
哦，克莱图斯表弟！
- 是的！
Did somebody say surprise?
有人说惊讶吗？
Yahoo!
- So much for my new monitor.
雅虎！
- 我的新显示器就这么多了。
- Yeah, that's fine.
It's also stupid.
- 是的，没关系。
这也是愚蠢的。
No one's going to eat
at a restaurant
没有人会去吃饭
在一家餐馆
that only serves potatoes.
只供应土豆。
- Oh, boy!
- Potatoes!
- 哦，孩子！
- 土豆！
- Hey, everybody,
- 嘿，大家，
this place sells
nothing but potatoes!
这个地方卖
除了土豆什么都没有！
- Potato?
Ooh!
- 土豆？
哦！
Hey, there's a new potato
restaurant across the street!
嘿，新土豆来了
街对面的餐厅！
- I never say no
to a starchy tuber.
- 我从不说不
到淀粉块茎。
Bleh.
[giggles]
布莱赫。
[咯咯笑]
- Oh, boy!
[indistinct chatter]
- 哦，孩子！
[模糊的喋喋不休]
- Run to the potatoes, Sir!
- 跑到土豆那里去，先生！
- I'm going to need this
for spuds!
- 我需要这个
为了马铃薯！
- [gasps]
Where's everybody going?
- [喘气]
大家都去哪儿了？
- One of everything, please.
- 一切都请来一份。
- A bunch of potatoes,
with extra peel.
- 一堆土豆，
有额外的果皮。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Karen?
- Yes, dear?
凯伦？
- 是的亲爱的？
- People are idiots.
- Yes, dear.
- 人们都是白痴。
- 是的亲爱的。
- Wait, Larry!
- 等等，拉里！
Wouldn't you like a nice,
protein-packed Krabby Patty?
难道你不想有一个美好的，
富含蛋白质的蟹肉饼？
- Yeah, sorry, bro,
but Larry needs to carbo load.
- 是的，对不起，兄弟，
但拉里需要补充碳水化合物。
Weirdo.
- Oh.
怪人。
- 哦。
That was me last customer.
- Hmm.
那是我最后一个顾客。
- 唔。
Maybe I can work this
to my advantage.
也许我可以做这个
对我有利。
- Oh, me restaurant.
- 哦，我的餐厅。
[sobs]
[抽泣]
- [hums melody]
- [哼唱旋律]
- Order up.
- 订购。
Order up.
订购吧。
- Aw, business
a little slow today, Krabs?
- 噢，生意
今天有点慢吗，蟹蟹？
- That Spud Bucket has
siphoned off all me customers!
- 那个马铃薯桶有
吸走了我所有的顾客！
- My family's new restaurant
has put you out of business.
- 我家的新餐厅
让你破产了。
You may as well
just give me the formula.
你也可以
只要给我公式即可。
You got no use for it now.
现在你已经没有用了。
- [sighs] You're right.
- [叹气]你是对的。
Boyo, come here.
博约，过来。
[face beeping]
[脸嘟嘟]
- Oh!
- 哦！
- You win, Plankton.
- 你赢了，浮游生物。
Since no one wants
Krabby Patties anymore,
既然没有人想要
不再是蟹肉饼了
me formula is worthless.
我的公式毫无价值。
- Yes!
- 是的！
With this worthless formula,
I can take over the world!
有了这个毫无价值的公式，
我可以征服世界！
- Does that make your plan
- 这符合你的计划吗
for world domination
worthless, too?
为了统治世界
也一文不值？
- Wait a minute.
[sighs]
- 等一下。
[叹气]
Oh, no.
Karen, take me home.
哦，不。
凯伦，带我回家。
- Oh, muffin.
- 哦，松饼。
- [giggles] [cackles]
- [咯咯笑] [咯咯笑]
- What's so funny, Mr. Krabs?
- Oh, nothing.
- 蟹老板，有什么好笑的？
- 哦，没什么。
I just sent a series of events
in motion
我刚刚发送了一系列事件
在运动中
that will soon solve
all our problems.
这很快就会解决
我们所有的问题。
- How am I going to shut down
that stupid Spud Bucket?
- 我要如何关闭
那个愚蠢的马铃薯桶？
- Why don't you call
the health inspector?
- 你为什么不打电话
卫生督察？
He shuts us down every week.
他每周都会让我们关门。
- Karen, you're a genius.
- 凯伦，你是个天才。
And since I built you,
I'm a double genius.
自从我建造了你，
我是一个双重天才。
[phone beeps]
[电话嘟嘟声]
- Bikini Bottom
Health Department.
- 比基尼下装
卫生部门。
- Just look at it.
- 看看它。
This joint is completely
infested with vermin.
这个联合完全是
充满害虫。
The vermins are even
preparing the food.
害虫甚至
准备食物。
[all laughing and humming]
[大家大笑和哼唱]
- Oh my.
- 天哪。
This restaurant
doesn't deserve an A.
这家餐厅
不值得获得A。
[cash register chiming]
[收银机提示音]
It deserves a triple A plus!
它值得获得 3A 加分！
- What?
- Whoo-hoo! Thank you.
- 什么？
- 呼呼！谢谢。
That's right neighborly.
这就是邻里关系吧。
- And thank you, sir,
for your generous donation
- 谢谢你，先生，
感谢您的慷慨捐赠
to the Health Inspector
Benevolent Fund.
给卫生督察
慈善基金。
- Always ready to help
the less fortunate.
- 随时准备提供帮助
较不幸运的人。
- Eh.
- 呃。
[upbeat country music]
[欢快的乡村音乐]
Huh?
啊？
So you want customers, eh?
所以你想要客户，是吗？
I'll give you a customer.
我会给你一个客户。
- Howdy, son.
- 你好，儿子。
What you got there?
你在那里得到了什么？
- I brought you a restaurant
warming present, Dad.
- 我给你带来了一家餐馆
温暖的礼物，爸爸。
Behold, the Insatiable Bulk!
看哪，贪得无厌的大块头！
Come on in.
It's all you can eat.
进来吧。
这就是你能吃的一切。
- Oh, boy!
- 哦，孩子！
I can eat this.
I can eat all of this!
我可以吃这个。
这些我都能吃！
[munching]
I can eat this!
[咀嚼]
我可以吃这个！
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
I can eat... I...
aww.
我可以吃……我……
哇。
[chomps]
[咀嚼]
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
- Hey!
- [screams]
- 嘿！
- [尖叫]
- So long, Spud Bucket.
- 再见，马铃薯桶。
- Whoo-hoo!
Yeehaw!
- 呼呼！
耶哈！
- Huh?
- 啊？
- Well, I just have
to thank you.
- 嗯，我刚刚
谢谢你。
This Patrick feller
is the Jim dandiest
这位帕特里克·费勒
是最花花公子的吉姆
tater masher I ever did see.
我见过的马铃薯捣碎器。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Ah.
啊。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
- [groans] Barnacles!
- [呻吟]藤壶！
Ow!
- [giggles]
噢！
- [咯咯笑]
Things are going
even better than I hoped.
事情进展顺利
甚至比我希望的还要好。
- I love when you get
all Machiavellian, Mr. Krabs.
- 我喜欢你得到的时候
蟹老板，都是马基雅维利主义者。
- I got a load of potatoes
for the, uh, Spud Bucket.
- 我有一大堆土豆
对于，呃，马铃薯桶。
- Hold on.
- 坚持，稍等。
I've got a delivery, too.
我也有快递了
Fire in the hole!
洞里着火了！
[explosion]
[爆炸]
Huh?
Ah.
啊？
啊。
♪ ♪
- [chomps] Mm.
- [咀嚼] 嗯。
This tater shrapnel
is better than Frenchy fries.
这块土豆弹片
比炸薯条更好。
- Mm-hmm!
- 嗯嗯！
- Your awful Spud Bucket
has ruined
- 你那可怕的土豆桶
已经毁了
my plans to conquer the world.
我征服世界的计划。
Now what am I supposed to do?
现在我该怎么办？
- Well, why don't you
come work for us?
- 好吧，你为什么不呢？
来为我们工作吗？
- The Spud Bucket
is a family business,
- 土豆桶
是一家家族企业，
and you're family, son.
儿子，你们是家人。
- Well, if I can't sabotage 'em,
- 好吧，如果我不能破坏他们，
annihilate 'em, or squelch 'em,
I might as well join 'em.
消灭他们，或者镇压他们，
我不妨加入他们。
[humming melody]
[哼唱的旋律]
Ah, hey!
啊，嘿！
One Spud du Jour.
一份土豆泥。
♪ ♪
Yep, you know,
cooking food that people
是的，你知道，
烹饪人们的食物
really want to eat actually
makes me pretty happy.
其实真的很想吃
让我很高兴。
- Your tater, sir.
- Oh, boy!
- 你的土豆泥，先生。
- 哦，孩子！
[chomps]
[咀嚼]
Bleh!
哎呀！
Eeeh!
Excuse me, what is in
this peculiar potato?
打扰一下，里面有什么
这种奇特的土豆？
- That's a Potato a la Plankton.
- 那是浮游生物土豆。
With just a pinch of chum
for flavor.
只需一点密友
为了味道。
- Oh, no.
You're the chef?
- 哦，不。
你是厨师吗？
Everyone,
put down your potatoes.
大家，
放下你的土豆。
Plankton is in the kitchen!
浮游生物在厨房里！
- [gags]
- [笑声]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[all spit]
[全吐]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- [sighs]
- I don't get it.
- [叹气]
- 我不明白。
What happened?
发生了什么？
- Guess our tater restaurant
is a big fat failure.
- 猜猜我们的土豆泥餐厅
是一个巨大的脂肪失败。
- Ah, well.
You win some and you lose some.
- 啊，好吧。
你赢得了一些，也失去了一些。
Cousin Cletus!
克莱图斯表弟！
Another surprise, please.
- [giggles]
再来一个惊喜，拜托。
- [咯咯笑]
[melodic horn honking]
[旋律喇叭鸣响]
- So long, son!
- 再见，儿子！
- We're off to buy
a football team.
- 我们去买
一支足球队。
[honks]
[喇叭]
- [cackles]
- [咯咯笑]
Turns out me formula's
worth something after all.
结果我的公式
毕竟值得一些东西。
Who's the loser now, Plankton?
Surprise!
浮游生物，现在谁是输家？
惊喜！
- Did somebody say surprise?
Yah!
- 有人说惊讶吗？
啊！
- [together] Surprise.
- [一起] 惊喜。
[both groan]
[两人都呻吟]
[bright music]
[明亮的音乐]
♪ ♪
- I love going to the movies.
- 我喜欢去看电影。
The sticky floors
make me feel grounded.
粘乎乎的地板
让我感到踏实。
- I can't wait for you
to see this movie, SpongeBob.
- 我等不及你了
看这部电影，海绵宝宝。
It's the funniest thing
I've never seen in your life.
这是最好笑的事
我一生中从未见过。
There's this one part
where this guy...
有这么一段
这家伙哪里...
[laughs]
- Two combos, please.
[笑]
- 请给我两个组合。
- Is wearing a hat.
[laughing]
- 戴着帽子。
[笑]
- No spoilers, Patrick.
- 没有剧透，帕特里克。
[soaring orchestral music]
【高亢的管弦乐】
♪ ♪
"Prudence in Love"?
“爱情中的谨慎”？
That doesn't sound funny.
这听起来并不好笑。
Patrick, are you sure
we're in the right theater?
帕特里克，你确定吗
我们在正确的剧院吗？
- [laughs] Shh!
- [笑]嘘！
♪ ♪
- I love you, Prudence.
- And I you, Nathaniel.
- 我爱你，普鲁登丝。
- 我和你，纳撒尼尔。
- But I love you more, Prudence.
- 但我更爱你，普鲁登丝。
- Then I love you slightly more
than that, Nathaniel.
- 那我爱你多一点
不仅如此，纳撒尼尔。
- It's not
a competition, Prudence.
- 不是
一场比赛，普鲁登斯。
- But if it were,
I'd be winning.
- 但如果是这样的话
我会赢的。
- Aw, this is so sweet.
- 噢，这太甜了。
[whispers]
But it's not funny.
[窃窃私语]
但这并不好笑。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- But your laughter
is so infectious.
- 但你的笑声
太有感染力了。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- And just then, all the years
- 就在那时，所有这些年
of excessive laughing
finally took their toll,
过度大笑的
终于付出了代价，
and SpongeBob's funny bone
got stuck in high gear.
和海绵宝宝的有趣骨头
陷入高速档。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- It's not
that funny, SpongeBob.
- 不是
真有趣，海绵宝宝。
- [continues laughing]
- [继续笑]
- Hey, what are you laughing at?
- 嘿，你笑什么？
This is a melodrama,
not a comedy.
这是一部情节剧，
不是喜剧。
- Yes!
Take a hike, Chuckles.
- 是的！
去远足吧，咯咯。
[audience booing]
[观众嘘声]
- Can you believe this guy,
- 你能相信这个人吗
laughing all through
the movie like that?
自始至终都在笑
电影是这样的吗？
- Who is making all that noise?
- 是谁发出这么大的噪音？
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- All right, laughing boy,
- 好吧，爱笑的男孩，
take your hardy har hars
outside!
带上你坚强的哈哈斯
外面！
[audience cheering]
[观众欢呼]
- Oh!
- 哦！
[laughs]
Huh? Uh-oh.
[笑]
啊？呃哦。
Why can't...
why can't I stop laughing?
为什么不能...
为什么我无法停止笑？
[laughs]
[笑]
Oh, what am I going to do?
[giggles]
哦，我该怎么办？
[咯咯笑]
I'll just have to...
hold it in.
我只需要...
坚持住。
[snickers]
[窃笑]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[muffled chuckling]
[低声笑]
I know.
I'll just hold my breath.
我知道。
我会屏住呼吸。
[inhales deeply]
[深吸一口气]
- No doubt about it, sir.
- 毫无疑问，先生。
You look fantastic in that hat.
你戴那顶帽子看起来棒极了。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- Oh, I look fantastic, huh?
- Oh, wait.
- 哦，我看起来棒极了，是吧？
- 哦，等等。
I'm not laughing at you.
我不是在笑你。
I really like that hat.
[laughing]
我真的很喜欢那顶帽子。
[笑]
- [sobbing]
- [抽泣]
- You're crying
over spilled milk!
- 你在哭
牛奶洒了！
[laughs]
Sorry! Sorry. Sorry.
[笑]
抱歉！对不起。对不起。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
OK, if I can just make it
to the kitchen,
好吧，如果我能做到的话
到厨房，
nobody will hear me laughing.
没有人会听到我笑。
[chuckles]
[笑声]
- SpongeBob,
kindly get in the kitchen.
- 海绵宝宝，
请进厨房。
And off of my face!
- Your face?
然后从我脸上消失！
- 你的脸？
[laughs]
[笑]
- What's so funny about my face?
- 我的脸有什么好笑的？
- Well, there's nothing
funny about your...
- 嗯，没什么
有趣的是你的...
face.
[laughs]
脸。
[笑]
- Don't laugh at me.
- 别笑我。
I laugh at you.
Ha!
我笑你。
哈!
Don't listen to him.
You're beautiful.
别听他的。
你非常美。
Mwah.
哇。
- Nobody will hear
my laughs in here.
- 没有人会听到
我的笑声就在这里。
[groans]
[laughs]
[呻吟]
[笑]
- Hey, I'm eating here!
- 嘿，我在这里吃饭！
- Why is the restaurant
laughing at us?
- 为什么是餐厅
嘲笑我们？
- [laughs]
- Huh?
- [笑]
- 啊？
[growls]
[咆哮]
- [laughing]
- SpongeBob!
- [笑]
- 海绵宝宝！
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- Your little laughing prank
- 你的小恶作剧
just scared away
all the customers.
刚刚被吓跑了
所有的顾客。
Explain yourself, boyo!
解释一下你自己，男孩！
- He's laughing
at my face, Mr. Krabs.
- 他在笑
就在我面前，蟹老板。
- Oh, I'm not laughing at you,
Squidward.
-哦，我不是在笑你，
章鱼哥。
[stifled laughter]
I'm not laughing at anything.
[抑制笑声]
我没有笑任何事。
[laughs]
Mr. Krabs, what do I do?
[笑]
蟹老板，我该怎么办？
- Think of happy thoughts
and just knock it off!
- 想想快乐的想法
然后把它关掉！
- I am offended!
- 我很生气！
There is no one here
to take my Fifi's order!
这里没有人
接受我菲菲的订单！
- Oh, gold-plated sorries,
Lady Upturn.
- 哦，镀金抱歉，
女士逆袭。
Mr. Squidward will take
章鱼哥先生将采取
your very important order
right away.
您非常重要的订单
马上。
- Whoa!
I need an ambulance.
- 哇！
我需要一辆救护车。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- How dare you laugh
at my misfortune!
- 你怎么敢笑
我的不幸！
Mr. Krabs,
fire this cretin at once!
蟹老板先生，
立刻开火这个白痴！
- You heard her.
- 你听到她的声音了。
Come back when you're not
a giggling idiot.
当你不在的时候回来吧
一个傻笑的白痴。
- Don't come back?
- 不回来吗？
But, Mr. Krabs,
I'm not laughing on purpose.
但是，蟹老板，
我不是故意笑的
[laughs]
- [gasps]
[笑]
- [喘气]
He's laughing at you, Fifi
他在笑你，菲菲
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
[snarling and chomping]
[咆哮和咀嚼]
- I'm sorry, Fifi.
- 对不起，菲菲。
I'm a monster!
我是一个怪物！
[laughing]
[笑]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
♪ ♪
I got to hide.
我得躲起来。
That way, my laughter
won't hurt anyone else.
这样我的笑声
不会伤害其他人。
[laughs]
OK, good.
[笑]
好的，很好。
It's dark.
天黑了。
If there's nothing to see,
there's nothing to laugh at.
如果没什么可看的
没有什么好笑的。
Right?
正确的？
[snickering]
[窃笑]
- Today, we will be
operating on a robot.
- 今天，我们将
在机器人上操作。
- Oh, robot.
- How exciting.
- 哦，机器人。
- 多么令人兴奋啊。
- What will they think of next?
- 接下来他们会想到什么？
- I will begin
by loosening the first bolt.
- 我会开始
松开第一个螺栓。
Nurse, wrench.
护士，扳手。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Wow.
This is really on tight.
哇。
这实在是太紧了。
Nurse, sponge.
护士，海绵。
- Ooh.
[laughs]
- 哦。
[笑]
- Laughing is not allowed
in the operating room.
- 不允许笑
在手术室里。
Get out of here!
离开这里！
[electricity crackles]
[电流爆裂声]
[tense music]
[紧张的音乐]
- [laughs] I am the surgeon now.
- [笑]我现在是外科医生。
I am the surgeon now.
我现在是外科医生。
- Ooh.
- Ah.
- 哦。
- 啊。
- Ooh.
- Fascinating.
- 哦。
- 迷人。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- [laughing]
- [grumbles]
- [笑]
- [抱怨]
- That is not funny.
- 这不好笑。
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
The cemetery.
墓地。
There's nothing funny
in a cemetery.
没有什么好笑的
在一个墓地里。
[snickering]
[窃笑]
Maybe I'll just live
the rest of my life here.
也许我就这样活着
我的余生都在这里。
[somber music]
[忧郁的音乐]
[muffled laughter]
[低沉的笑声]
♪ ♪
- [sobbing]
- [gasps]
- [抽泣]
- [喘气]
Clowns?
Oh, no.
小丑？
哦，不。
- There are two kinds of clowns
in this world,
- 小丑有两种
在这个世界上，
clowns that are only laughing
on the outside,
只会笑的小丑
在外面，
and clowns that are
only laughing on the inside.
和小丑
只是内心在笑。
Sparkle Nose the Clown was both,
闪闪鼻子的小丑两者兼而有之，
and that's what made him a star.
这就是他成为明星的原因。
[horn honks]
[喇叭鸣响]
[horns honking]
- So solemn.
I should leave.
- 如此庄严。
我该离开了。
Whoa!
[horn honks]
哇！
[喇叭鸣响]
Hey!
[laughs]
嘿！
[笑]
Holy herring,
I'm squatting on a corpse.
圣鲱鱼，
我蹲在一具尸体上。
- Would you get off my chest?
- 你能离开我的胸口吗？
- [laughs]
Huh? You're alive?
- [笑]
啊？你还活着吗？
- Of course, I'm alive.
- 当然，我还活着。
This is a living funeral,
and you're ruining it.
这是一场活生生的葬礼
而你正在毁掉它。
- Sorry.
- 对不起。
I'm not laughing at you,
Sparkle Nose.
我不是在笑你
闪闪发光的鼻子。
Oh, I'll just
get off of your chest.
哦，我就
从你的胸口下来。
Whoa!
哇！
[whimsical music]
[异想天开的音乐]
- I'm allergic to wreath pollen!
- 我对花环花粉过敏！
Eeh, ah...
诶诶诶……
- Cheese it, he's going to blow!
- 干酪吧，他要爆炸了！
- Achoo!
- 阿呼！
- Sorry.
[laughs]
- 对不起。
[笑]
- You turned my clown funeral
into a joke!
变成笑话了！
[honking]
[鸣喇叭]
- [laughs]
Forgive me, Sparkle Nose!
- [笑]
原谅我，闪闪的鼻子！
[laughs]
[笑]
- Hours later, poor SpongeBob
- 几个小时后，可怜的海绵宝宝
still could not stop laughing.
还是忍不住笑了。
And his laughing mouth
got so big,
还有他那张笑起来的嘴
变得这么大了，
it took over his whole face.
它占据了他的整张脸。
- Oh, I'm tired of all this
cackling and chuckling.
- 哦，我厌倦了这一切
咯咯笑。
I feel more like I want to...
我感觉我更想...
Oh, "Weep"?
"The saddest movie ever."
噢，“哭泣”？
“有史以来最悲伤的电影。”
That's it!
就是这样！
A movie started my laughing.
Maybe a movie can stop it.
一部电影让我笑了。
也许一部电影可以阻止它。
- [sobbing]
- [抽泣]
- [snickering]
- [窃笑]
[laughs]
[笑]
- Shh!
- I'm sorry.
- 嘘！
- 对不起。
[laughs]
I can't hold it!
[笑]
我快撑不住了！
[laughing and slapping]
[大笑并拍手]
- [laughs]
- Huh?
- [笑]
- 啊？
- [laughing]
- Grandma?
- [笑]
- 奶奶？
You can't stop laughing either?
- Of course not, dearie.
你也笑得停不下来吗？
- 当然不是，亲爱的。
My funny bone
got stuck years ago
我的搞笑骨头
几年前就被困住了
when I was your age.
- Your funny bone?
当我像你这个年纪的时候。
- 你有趣的骨头？
- That's right.
- 这是正确的。
It happens
to everyone in our family.
它发生了
给我们家里的每个人。
Be proud of that laugh,
SpongeBob.
为那笑容感到骄傲
海绵宝宝。
To be a SquarePants
is to laugh loud at life.
成为一个方裤
就是对生活大声笑。
Enjoy a good laugh with me.
- Oh, thanks, Grandma.
和我一起开心地笑吧。
-哦，谢谢，奶奶。
- These tearjerker movies
always crack me up.
- 这些催人泪下的电影
总是让我开心。
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
- [sobbing]
- [抽泣]
I'm all out of popcorn.
我的爆米花已经吃完了。
Now it's a tragedy.
现在这是一场悲剧。
[sobbing]
[抽泣]